Guide to the Tanka Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Tanka collection
1600-1950
Tibet MSS 62
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
6.3
(77 boxes)
The collection consists of tankas, which are Buddhist scrolls or fabric temple banners, chiefly Tibetan, but also Nepalese, Bhutanese, Indian and Chinese, which bear religious images, circa 1600-circa 1950. Some tankas also bear inscriptions on their versos.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired from various sources. For further information consult entries for individual tankas in the guide to the collection.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Tankas
Tankas, also known as thangkas, are hanging scrolls or fabric temple banners that consist of a painted picture panels (called mélong in Tibetan, which means 'mirror'), usually depicting buddhas, mandalas, or great practitioners, which are sewn into or bordered by a textile mountings. Tankas are intended to serve as records of, and guides for, contemplative experiences and visualizations.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 77 tankas, chiefly Tibetan, but also Nepalese, Bhutanese, Indian and Chinese, which bear religious images, circa 1600-circa 1950. Some tankas also bear inscriptions on their versos.
Divinities represented in the collection include Akṣobhya, Amitābha, Amitāyus, Avalokiteśvara, Bardo Thodol deities, Bhaiṣajyaguru, Dorje Shugden, Garwai Nagpo Damchen, Hayagrīva, Mahākāla, Palden Lhamo, Prajñāpāramitā, Rāhula, Sitātapatrā, Tārā, Vajrabhairava, Vajrapāṇi, Vajrasattva, Vajrayoginī, Vasudhārā, and Viśrāvaṇa.
Buddhist practitioners with portraits in the collection include Gautama Buddha, his arhats (disciples), Kloṅ-chen-pa Dri-med-'od-zer, Lobsang Chökyi Gyaltsen, Mi-la-ras-pa, Ṅag-dbaṅ-blo-bzaṅ-rgya-mtsho, Padma Sambhava, Tsoṅ-kha-pa Blo-bzaṅ-grags-pa, and Yungtön Dorjepel, as well as unidentified Karmapa abbots and an unidentified Sa-skya-pa lama.
Portrayals of inanimate objects and locations include srid-pa-ho (astrological divination charts), a srid-pa'i-'khor-lo (wheel of life), rgyan-tshogs (offerings), a stupa and a mandala.
Identified artists in the collection consist of Tsewang Norbu, an artist active in Darjeeling, India, circa 1865, as well as Rin-zin (or Rig-zin), a artist active in Sikkim, India, circa 1950.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Identified Creators, circa 1865-circa 1950. II. Identified Subjects, circa 1600-circa 1950.
Buddhist art and symbolism -- China -- Tibet Autonomous Region; Buddhist painting -- China -- Tibet Autonomous Region; Buddhist gods in art; Tankas (Tibetan scrolls); Painting -- Bhutan; Painting -- China; Painting -- China -- Tibet Autonomous Region; Painting -- India; Painting -- Nepal; Tankas (scrolls or banners)
- Identified Creators, circa 1865-circa 1950; Series I; (8 paintings)
  Arrangement
  This series is organized alphabetically by the artist, followed by groups of tankas by an unidentified Tibetan and Nepalese artists.
  Scope and Contents
  Tankas created by identified Indian artists or attributed to unidentified Tibetan and Nepalese artists.
  - Rin-zin (or Rig-zin)
    Biographical/Historical note
    Rin-zin (or Rig-zin) was an artist active in Sikkim, India, circa 1950.
    - Tanka of Mañjuśrī, circa 1950; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 63 x 49 cm. bordered with silk brocade 130 x 97 cm. in a frame. (Box 1 (Oversize))
      Mañjuśrī is a bodhisattva associated with transcendent wisdom.
      General note
      Former call number: TIB. 68.1.
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      Gift of Marjorie Knight Macrae, 1968.
      Custodial History
      Publisher Elliott Beach Macrae (1900-1968) was given the tanka by Tashi Namgyal (1893-1963), the Maharaja Chogyal of Sikkim, circa 1950.
      A Sikkimese watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Mañjuśrī, accompanied by a white Tārā with seven eyes and Viśrāvaṇa, the chief of the Four Heavenly Kings. The figures are reportedly modeled after the Macrae family.
      Inscriptions in Tibetan on verso.
      The tanka includes a silk cover and ribbons.
  - Tsewang Norbu
    Tsewang Norbu was an artist in Darjeeling, India.
    - Tanka of Gautama Buddha, circa 1865; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 104 x 74 cm. bordered with silk 104 x 73 cm. (Box 2 (Oversize))
      Gautama Buddha (circa 563 BCE-483 BCE), also known as Śākyamuni, was a spiritual teacher from ancient India who founded Buddhism.
      Former call number: TIB. 59.1.
      Gift of Martin J. Gerson, 1959.
      A watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Gautama Buddha surrounded by nine figures. The painting also depicts the male and female patron on the painting in Sanskrit expressed in phonetic Tibetan, Bhalaram Norbu and Bhanavati Drolma.
      Inscription in Tibetan on the verso, which venerates Gautama Buddha, the patrons, and the artist.
  - Unidentified Tibetan Artist
    Two tankas created by an unidentified Tibetan artist based on Jātakas, a body of literature native to India concerning the previous births (jāti) of the Gautama Buddha.
    Gift of Edna Bryner Schwab, 1967.
    - Tanka of Gautama Buddha and scenes from the Vessantara Jātaka, circa 1700-circa 1800; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 65.5 x 40.0 cm. bordered with silk 134 x 76 cm. (Box 3 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 67.3.
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Gautama Buddha surrounded by scenes from "Vessantara Jātaka," In the story a compassionate prince gives away everything he owns, including his wife and children, thereby displaying the virtue of perfect charity.
      The tanka includes a silk cover.
    - Tanka of Gautama Buddha and scenes from the Ruru Deer Jātaka, circa 1700-circa 1800; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 65.5 x 39.0 cm. bordered with silk 134 x 76 cm. (Box 4 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 67.2.
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Gautama Buddha surrounded by scenes from "The Ruru Deer Jātaka," In the story the Ruru Deer saves man, who then betrays the deer, but the deer survives and teaches.
  - Unidentified Nepalese Artist
    Four tankas created by an unidentified northern Nepalese artist.
    Purchased by Joseph F. Weiler in Nepal. Gifts of Joseph F. Weiler and Eliza Weiler, 1983.
    - Tanka of Amitāyus, circa 1900-circa 1950; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 57 x 39 cm. mounted on cotton 87 x 63 cm. (Box 5 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 83.2.
      A watercolor painting on cotton that depicts a red Amitāyus seated on a multicolored lotus accompanied by three smaller figures above and six human figures below in Nepalese dress and holding black umbrellas.
    - Tanka of Avalokiteśvara, circa 1900-circa 1950; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 54 x 41 cm. mounted on cotton 93 x 79 cm. (Box 6 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 83.1.
      A watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Avalokiteśvara seated on a pink lotus accompanied by smaller figures, as well as Amitābha above and Padma Sambhav below.
      Inscription in Tibetan on the verso. Consecrated by a lama to address an illness.
    - Tanka of Bardo Thodol Deities, circa 1900-circa 1950; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 77.5 x 46.5 cm. mounted on cotton 108 x 67 cm (Box 7 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 83.3.
      A watercolor painting on cotton that depicts the 42 Peaceful Deities of Bardo with Samantabhadra in a rainbow framed circle accompanied by human figures below in Nepalese dress and holding black umbrellas.
      Inscription in Tibetan on the verso. Nine of the inscriptions are consecrations of the divinities on the recto.
    - Tanka of Padma Sambhava, circa 1900-circa 1950; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 21 x 16 cm. mounted on cotton and silk 58 x 42 cm. (Box 8 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 83.4
      A watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Padma Sambhava seated on a lotus throne.
- Identified Subjects, circa 1600-circa 1950; Series II; (69 paintings)
  Series II is organized alphabetically by subject.
  Tankas created by unidentified artists from Tibet, Nepal, Bhutan, and China of identified subjects.
  - Akṣobhya
    Akṣobhya is one of the Five Wisdom Buddhas, a product of the Adi-Buddha, who represents consciousness as an aspect of reality.
    - Tanka of Akṣobhya, circa 1850-circa 1950; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 65.0 x 44.5 cm. borderd with silk brocade 114 x 71 cm. (Box 9 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 76.3.
      Purchased in Nepal by Ann Rohrer in 1968. Gift of Ann Rohrer, 1976.
      A Nepalese watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Akṣobhya surrounded by 516 miniature emanations of himself. All of the figures are outlined in red on gold.
  - Amitābha
    Amitābha, also known as "The Buddha of Infinite Light," is a celestial buddha known for his longevity and the deep awareness of individualities.
    - Tanka of Amitābha, circa 1700-circa 1800; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 61.5 x 41.0 cm. mounted on silk brocade 107 x 58 cm. (Box 10 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 85.11.
      Gift of an anonymous donor (Yale 1929), 1985.
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Amitābha seated on a lotus throne presiding over Sukhāvatī, his celestial realm, surrounded by eight bodhisattvas and telve smaller buddhas and divinities, and behind a lake with two babies upon a lotus.
    - Tanka of Amitābha, circa 1800-circa 1900; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 65 x 46 cm. mounted on silk brocade 112 x 71 cm. (Box 11 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 65.1.
      Gift of Wesley E. Needham, 1965.
      An eastern Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Amitābha surrounded by miniature figures.
  - Amitāyus
    Amitāyus is also used for the Sambhogakāya aspect of Amitābha, particularly associated with longevity.
    - Tanka of Amitāyus, circa 1700-circa 1800; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 70.0 x 45.5 bordered with silk brocade 118 x 72 cm. (Box 12 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 62.2.
      Purchased from Vivian Rose, 1962.
      A watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Amitāyus, a deity associated with longevity, surrounded with 144 miniature emanations of himself.
      Inscription in Tibetan on the verso.
  - Arhats
    Arhats, also known as Sthaviras, were sixteen individuals selected by Gautama Buddha from among his disciples and to remain in the world and protect the Dharma for as long as beings are capable of benefitting from the teachings. The sixteen arhats are usually depicted in tankas accompanied by their two attendants, Hva Shang and Upasaka Dharmatala, as well as by the Four Great Kings.
    - Tanka of two arhats accompanied by Upasaka Dharmatala, circa 1700-circa 1800; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 63 x 42 cm. bordered with silk brocade 132 x 81 cm. (Box 13 (Art))
      Former call number: TIB. 62.5.
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts two of the sixteen arhats, the original followers of the Buddha, accompanied by Upasaka Dharmatala, a patron of the Dharma, attendant of the sixteen arhats and a manifestation of Avalokiteśvara.
    - Tanka of two arhats, undated; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 70 x 46 bordered with silk brocade 144 x 74 cm. (Box 14 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 60.1.
      Transferred from the Yale University Art Gallery, 1960. Former Art Gallery No. 1951.51.52.
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts two of the sixteen arhats, the original followers of the Buddha.
      The painting is one of a set of nine paintings and is marked "Right-two" in Tibetan on its verso.
      Inscriptions in Tibetan on the verso.
  - Avalokiteśvara
    Avalokiteśvara is a bodhisattva that embodies the speech of all the buddhas and incarnation of their compassion.
    - Tanka of Avalokiteśvara, circa 1700-circa 1800; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 91.5 x 60.0 cm. mounted on silk in a frame 101 x 67 cm. (Box 15 (Art))
      Former call number: TIB. 85.2.
      Gift of Orson L. St. John, 1985.
      A Tibetan or Chinese watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Avalokiteśvara with a eleven heads and eight arms standing on a lotus.
    - Tanka of Avalokiteśvara, circa 1800-circa 1850; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 76 x 48 cm. bordered with silk brocade 133 x 76 cm. (Box 16 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 67.8.
      An Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Avalokiteśvara accompanied by celestial scenes and divinities, as well as a figure of a Tibetan king.
    - Tanka of Avalokiteśvara, circa 1800-circa 1900; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 65 x 42 cm. bordered with silk brocade 130 x 84 cm. (Box 17 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 66.2.
      Purchased from Tibet House, New Delhi, India, 1966.
      An eastern Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Avalokiteśvara accompanied by eight smaller figures.
    - Tanka of Avalokiteśvara, circa 1800-circa 1900; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 57.0 x 39.5 cm. bordered with silk brocade 115 x 70 cm (Box 18 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 85.12.
      An eastern Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts a white Avalokiteśvara with four arms seated on a pink lotus below Gautama Buddha, Vajrapāṇi, and Tsoṅ-kha-pa Blo-bzaṅ-grags-pa with two disciples, as well as above Manjushri, a green Tārā, and Vajrapāṇi.
    - Tanka of Avalokiteśvara, circa 1850-circa 1900; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 69 x 49 cm. bordered with silk brocade 122 x 78 cm. (Box 19 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 76.1.
      A southern Tibetan or Bhutanese watercolor painting on cottton that depicts Avalokiteśvara with four arms and accompanied by numerous smaller figures.
    - Tanka of Avalokiteśvara, circa 1950; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 45 x 31 cm. mounted on silk brocade 85 x 57 cm. (Box 20 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 76.2.
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cottton that depicts Avalokiteśvara with four arms and accompanied by Manjushri and Vajrapāṇi.
  - Bardo Thodol Deities
    The Bardo Thodol, also known as the Tibetan Book of the Dead, is a text used in Tibetan Buddhism to guide one through the experiences that the consciousness has after death, during the interval between death and the next rebirth. The first portion of the ritual is dedicated to the epiphany of the peaceful and wrathful bardo deities.
    - Tanka of the 58 Wrathful Deities of Bardo, circa 1600-circa 1700; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 74 x 47 cm. bordered with silk brocade 123 x 78 cm. (Box 21 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 67.19
      An Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts the 58 Wrathful Deities of Bardo.
    - Tanka of the 42 Peaceful Deities of Bardo, circa 1700-circa 1750; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 74 x 54 cm. bordered with silk brocade 125 x 85 cm. (Box 22 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 72.1.
      Purchased from Russell Trenholme, 1972.
      An Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts the 42 Peaceful Deities of Bardo accompanied by other figures and some inscriptions.
  - Bhaiṣajyaguru
    Bhaiṣajyaguru, also known as the Medicine Buddha, is the buddha of healing and medicine in Mahāyāna Buddhism. He is described as a doctor who cures suffering using the medicine of his teachings.
    - Tanka of Bhaiṣajyaguru, circa 1800-circa 1900; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 51 x 34 cm. bordered with silk brocade 101 x 69 cm. (Box 23 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 85.7.
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Bhaiṣajyaguru accompanied by seven emanations of himself and posited above a depiction of Mahākāla.
  - Dorje Shugden
    Dorje Shugden, also known as Dolgyal Shugden, a deity in the Dge-lugs-pa school of Buddhism, and regarded as a Dharma Protector or "guardian angel."
    - Tanka of Dorje Shugden, circa 1600-circa 1800; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 36.5 x 29.0 cm. bordered with silk brocade 85 x 60 cm. (Box 24 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 62.3.
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Dorje Shugden below three lamas and two deities and above three deities, as well as flanked by three smaller figures.
  - Garwai Nagpo Damchen
    Garwai Nagpo Damchen, also known as the Blacksmith, is the main attendant to Vajrasadhu, and the oath bound worldly protector of the Nyingma School.
    - Tanka of Garwai Nagpo Damchen, circa 1600-circa 1800; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 39.5 x 25.5 cm. bordered with silk brocade 78 x 51 cm. (Box 25 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 67.16.
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Garwai Nagpo Damchen holding a vajra hammer in his right hand, wearing a hat, and riding a goat. He is below Tsoṅ-kha-pa Blo-bzaṅ-grags-pa and two of his disciples.
  - Gautama Buddha
    - Tanka of Gautama Buddha, circa 1700-circa 1800; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 94.5 x 62.5 cm. in a frame 101 x 67 cm. (Box 26 (Art))
      Former call number: TIB. 85.1.
      A Tibetan or Chinese watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Gautama Buddha seated on a lotus accompanied by two lamas, four arhats, and several divinities, including Yama and Yami.
    - Tanka of Gautama Buddha, circa 1700-circa 1800; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 63.5 x 35.5 cm. bordered with silk brocade 105 x 55 cm. (Box 27 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 85.10.
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Gautama Buddha escorted by two bodhisattvas and blessing a lama above a scene of the lama accompanied by Sarasvatī, a guardian deity who upholds the teachings of Gautama Buddha by offering protection and assistance to practitioners.
    - Tanka of Gautama Buddha, circa 1700-circa 1900; 1 painting: gold ink on silk on rice paper 119 x 68 cm. (Box 28 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 67.4.
      A Chinese gold ink painting on black silk that depicts Gautama Buddha accompanied by smaller figures.
      Writing on the upper recto of the painting in Chinese, Manchu, Mongolian, and Tibetan.
      Inscription in French on verso.
    - Tanka of Gautama Buddha with eight arhats and two attendants, circa 1700-circa 1900; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton 98 x 63 cm. (Box 29 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 67.5.
      A Tibetan or Chinese watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Gautama Buddha accompanied by eight arhats and two attendants, probably Hva Shang and Upasaka Dharmatala. The tanka has painted borders that simulate silk brocade.
    - Tanka of Gautama Buddha, circa 1800-circa 1850; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 70 x 45 cm. bordered with silk 101 x 58 cm. (Box 30 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 63.1.
      Gift of Colonel Eric Foster Storm, 1963.
      A western Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Gautama Buddha accompanied by smaller figures, including a monkey. Several panels in the image contain inscriptions in cursive Tibetan script.
      Depiction of a stupa on the verso.
    - Tanka of Gautama Buddha, disciples, and the Thirty-five Buddhas of Confession, circa 1900-circa 1950; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 62.0 x 41.5 cm. bordered with silk brocade 90 x 65 cm. (Box 31 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 59.2.
      A western Tibetan or Nepalese watercolor painting on cotton, probably by an amateur artist that depicts Gautama Buddha seated on a lotus throne flanked by two of his chief disciples, Sāriputta and Moggallāna, and surrounded by the Thirty-five Buddhas of Confession.
      The tanka includes a silk cover
    - Tanka of Gautama Buddha, circa 1950; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 94 x 64 cm. (Box 32 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 66.1.
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton by a refugee painter that depicts Gautama Buddha accompanied by two buddha figures and two arhats.
    - Tanka of Gautama Buddha, disciples, and the Thirty-five Buddhas of Confession, undated; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 65.0 x 47.5 cm., unmounted and unbordered (Box 33 (Broadside))
      Former call number: TIB. 76.6.
      Gift of Norton Canfield, 1981.
      A western Tibetan or Nepalese watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Gautama Buddha surrounded by the Thirty-five Buddhas of Confession.
  - Gautama Buddha and Scenes from Jātakas
    Jātakas are a body of literature native to India concerning the previous births (jāti) of the Gautama Buddha.
    - Tanka of Gautama Buddha and scenes from the Starving Tigress Jātaka, circa 1700-1800; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 60 x 41 cm. bordered with silk brocade 135 x 81 cm. (Box 34 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 60.4.
      Transferred from the Yale University Divinity School Library, 1960. Gift of Orville Anderson Petty (Yale Ph.D. 1915, Hon. D.D. 1919).
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Gautama Buddha surrounded by scenes from "The Starving Tigress Jātaka." In the story a bodhisattva sees a starving tigress about to eat her own cubs, and the bodhisattva offers her his own body.
      Inscription in Tibetan on verso describes the position of the tanka in relation to other tankas.
  - Guhyasamāja
    Guhyasamāja is a blue-black Akṣobhyavajra, a form of Akṣobhya.
    - Tanka of Guhyasamāja, circa 1700-circa 1800; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 61 x 42 cm. bordered with silk brocade 112 x 58.5 cm. (Box 35 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 85.14.
      A Nepalese watercolor painting on cotton that depicts Guhyasamāja with a dark blue body, six arms, and three faces and in union with his consort as Sparshavajrā, as well as accompanied by forty-five figures.
  - Hayagrīva
    Hayagrīva is a fierce horse-faced deity who is powerful in driving off unconverted demonic forces.
    - Tanka of Hayagrīva, circa 1800-circa 1900; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 47 x 34 cm. bordered with silk brocade 102 x 66 cm (Box 36 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 62.4.
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton with embroidery that depicts Hayagrīva surrounded by emanations of himself and other figures.
      Inscription in Tibetan on verso.
    - Tanka of Hayagrīva, circa 1900-circa 1950; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 74 x 52 cm. bordered with brocade 152 x 102 cm. (Box 37 (Art))
      Former call number: TIB. 58.1.
      Gift of Chester Bowles (Yale 1924), 1958.
      Bowles was given the tanka by the King of Nepal, Tribhuvan Bir Bickrum Shah, circa 1951-1953.
      A Tibetan watercolor painting on cotton with embroidery that depicts Hayagrīva surrounded by thirty-six figures. The painting is mounted on brocade that depicts dragons.
  - Karmapa Abbots
    The Karmapa is the head of the Karma Kagyu, the largest sub-school of the Kagyupa, itself one of the four major schools of Tibetan Buddhism.
    - Tanka of a Karmapa Abbot, circa 1700-circa 1900; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 63 x 42 cm. bordered with silk brocade 122 x 84 cm. (Box 38 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 85.3.
      A watercolor painting on cotton that depicts an unidentified Karmapa abbot wearing a red hat and seated, as well as accompanied by smaller figures, including a lama and protective divinities. Consecrated on the verso by a lama.
      Depiction of a stupa and inscriptions in Tibetan on verso.
      Accompanied with an envelope from Hotel Mount Everest, Darjeeling, India, with notes about the tanka.
    - Tanka of a Karmapa Abbot, circa 1800-circa 1950; 1 painting: watercolor on cotton; 23.0 x 18.5 cm. mounted on silk brocade 48 x 40 cm. (Box 39 (Oversize))
      Former call number: TIB. 85.5.